Somehow
Elizabeth stopped war machines from destroying the world.
She couldn't save the civilisation of the old ones that was destroyed.
Obviously with life.
It's right.
She saved life
being devoured.
I need to know how Elizabeth stops the machines.
If I can find the weapons she built and use it,
the eclipse won't stand a chance
Going to the grave.
Lord,
It lived up to its name.
Millions of people
fought and died to give us about the time she needed to finish.
Zero Dawn.
The weapon she built.
It wasn't there.
I found out where she built it.
A secret base west of here.
Right.
Understand?
Fall
the capital of the Shadow Kharja,
I say you've been here before.
Obviously,
I've spent a lifetime trying to uncover the secrets of this world.
I'm heading down
a lifetime of failure.
I hit walls.
I could not break doors.
I could never breach until a Nora hundreds watched out of the savage beast for her all the deepest secrets of the Foley.
Hello,
nice tits.
But you will have an easier time with this door than I did years ago.
Hold for I tend to scan
genetic profile confirmed entry authorised
function function.
Not believe me.
Another way.
A little bit.
So back here.
Requesting access.
Request acknowledged.
Command functions available.
Do you wish to proceed?
I do.
Get me through this door.
Analysing primary access inoperable due to mechanical failure.
Emergency venting procedure likely to circumvent blockage.
Do you wish to proceed?
Yes.
Emergency.
You have everything that would draw attention.
We won't have this place to ourselves for long way.
Last I checked, I was the one risking my life down here.
Yes, fine.
Now will you please get moving?
It's so much to learn in less time than I'd hoped.
Welcome to Project Euro.
Hold on.
We found it.
Are you really so surprised?
Facility diagnostic.
Detect multiple failures.
A 10 thing repaired.
So what was this room then?
Entrance old, Perhaps.
Have a look around
from lamb staff to admin subject Another incident.
Thiss Morning's unfortunate incident with Dr Popovich is another example of receptions.
Need for additional support.
We appreciate that Zero Don is an immensely complicated project.
But is the staff who serve on the front line?
We're tired of being neglected as we have already requested.
We need human translators fluent in Polish for example, security staff who can subdue enraged embryologists, for example, and thermal sedatives to calm persons who are screaming in Polish, one hurling chairs and bases at reception staff, for example.
Yes, most of the candidates are reasonably come and well behaved, but we need help handling the exceptions to that rule.
Please respond
from reception staff to admin subject.
We need support to reception.
Staff continues to require additional support, managing senti candidates when they arrive at the facility.
Many are frightened or confused.
Some are highly agitated, thes air, not the sort of persons who are accustomed to having information withheld from them.
At minimum, we need human translators.
The Lang bots are not sufficient and mild sedatives.
For the extreme cases, any and all support would be welcome.
Perhaps you could start by responding to one of these males.
Please take a seat, then wait for your name to be called.
A selection of beverages and snacks are available.
A smaller room
from lounge staff to admin subject sound proving.
Would it be possible to improve the sound proofing between the are one and the lounge area?
Most of the candidates stay quiet during the presentation But the ones who scream or sub could be plainly heard by candidates waiting their turn in the lounge.
Just a thought
from lounge staff to admin subject.
Restock around for the fifth time.
Please restock the lounges.
Selection of herbal teas.
If I have to listen to one more egghead, throw a tantrum because we're out of the organic cucumber mentor Blackberry sage for ideals.
I am going to lose it.
Please respond.
And this time, no tempest in a teapot or steep demand jokes.
Okay,
Please proceed into viewing room one for an important message regarding the purpose of your visit.
What What's this place?
The holographic future.
See me Run
Initiating playback.
Welcome to Project Zero Dawn.
I am General Harris, chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff of the United States of America.
I'm sure you've heard the rumours that zero Dawn is a top secret super weapons programme.
The technological miracle that was safest from the Pharaoh plague.
If Operation Enduring Victory could hold off the robots long enough reason, I'm sure you've heard the rumours is that I'm the one who spread them and they're all lies.
Zero dawn is not a super weapons programme and it will not save us.
Nothing will save us
his way.
By the time the witch was noticed, it was already too late.
Nothing could stop the pharaoh plate
can It's robots will continue to replicate and devour the biosphere.
Life on Earth will be destroyed.
Our planet reduced to a barren sphere.
Global extinction is inevitable.
No matter how many we killed, robots just keep exponentially making more
because we have the deactivation codes way could shut them all down the entire slow.
But since the cryptographic protocols used Polly physic entangled reforms cracking a code said would take half a century at best.
We've got 16 months
exactly what you call us.
A five election.
The destruction of our biosphere is not the sort of apocalypse You gonna wait out in a fallout shelter or space station.
There will be no birth left to reclaim just a lifeless toxic rock with several million pharaoh robots on hibernating,
waiting for something to eat.
This is the horrible truths behind the lies of Operation Enduring Victory,
My lies, lies designed to inspire millions of innocents to sacrifice themselves in battle.
Why?
One reason
to buy time for you and the work you do here zero day the day that life on Earth ceases to exist is coming fast.
It cannot be stopped.
The hope of zero dawn is that something you might come after.
But I will leave.
A duel is about so back to shine That thing, Ray of light into the darkness.
Paris is out.
It doesn't make sense.
Life on Earth didn't cease to exist.
He said it could not be stopped, but it was somehow So how was it that saved us?
I've got to keep looking.
Find out how she did it.
Castrol's they got in through the vents.
Let nothing stop you from learning the truth.
Spread out if it moves telling What is this place?
Two.
Okay,
Spike
three.
We're too close to the tribal.
Primitive doubles, No
data points.
What did they continue
being with?
Suzanne Alpert, environmental scientist.
Dr.
I'm sorry, I wasn't just stating unity.
What were you thinking about, Dr?
Nothing.
The general said.
Not really.
I was on disses Ity East Response team and 2051 just after the second earthquake compromised the reactor.
I still dream about it after all these years.
The red zone, spreading on the imaging slowly so slowly, like a hand opening its fingers.
Your involvement in that event is why you were asked for by name.
Really, That's interesting because nothing worked.
Nothing could grow there again.
It was a catastrophic failure, but the red zone is a blip compared to global scale biomass reduction.
The biosphere and hydra favour collapse render the arts uninhabitable long before the robots finish us enduring victory.
Can't buy time against that, so you'd better show me what zero dawn really is.
Debriefing After presentation, one candidates must be allowed to ask questions and be given the necessary time to fully absorb the information they have received.
It is important to be aware that candidates have just been exposed to triggers for severe mental and emotional trauma.
Do not assume silence or outward calmness indicates acceptance.
It is essential to stress that all other options for combating the pharaoh plague and preserving the continuation of human life has been considered and found unworkable.
Communicate this fact calmly but clearly and firmly familiarise yourself with data on the catastrophic environmental impact of nuclear engagements versus the swarm attended B one and um feasibility of maintaining life in orbital, loner or undersea structures.
A dentist c one c two c.
Three so that you can counter candidates objections in depth.
If a candidate asks for time alone to review supplementary information, allow this without hesitation.
Be sure to inform security personnel so the candidate can be monitored for attempts at self harm.
Candidates should only be cleared to proceed to presentation, too.
If you believe their mental state is sufficiently stable, note that really time support will be available.
Value your focus.
Security and medical prices Teams are David.
I'm sure you now understand the urgency of why we brought you here in his.
Okay.
Hello, Captain.
Oh, Kilo.
Are you trying to thank me for not resisting?
I believe we couldn't negotiate a diplomatic solution when it came to my country's lithium.
It was always a swarm that would be sent to negotiate metallurgic International US Robot Command.
The markings changed, but the robots were the same.
You have had considerable experience in human robot conflict?
Yes, on DH.
I've got the prosthetic limbs to show it.
Yet I continue to face this horror.
Even though the challenge was great cyber warfare, I thought zero dog would be up a Manhattan project to generate the deactivation combs with The Resource is I had I estimated codebreaking to be a hopeless endeavour.
I was almost looking forward to being proved wrong.
Unfortunately, your estimation was correct, as your general Harris said.
So then you didn't bring me here to commiserate.
What is left?
Look, let's cut the mystery.
You're building a colony ship.
It's obvious and it's not gonna fly.
I mean, literally.
Remember the Odyssey, that multinational heap of space junk that's been a graveyard orbit since 57?
That went nowhere real slow, and you have to get somewhere real fast.
You have any idea the immensity of the challenge to prep a new colony ship in time?
To be clear, I'm not a worker on the project.
Do you even understand how few people that could save the whole generation ship concept is is not gonna happen.
It's the first thing you'd abandon in favour of embryonic CE for that kind of storage.
We're talking a lot of bolt, a lot of power, a lot of resources.
So even if you do it, even if you build it appointed its serious X There's no room for people on that thing.
All right.
If you try to remain calm, your people were busy.
If you think you're getting off this rock, know what's getting off medical?
There is some mistake.
I don't understand why I was brought here.
Why would you show me these things?
I know that there's already a lot to take in in the waiting area.
I was seated with a Nobel laureate in biophysics and a monk.
I think he spoke neither English nor Mandarin.
It is very strange.
And General Harris, What was he talking about?
The robot swarm the feral plague.
I understand.
It is terrible, but it really cannot be stopped.
Why tell us this?
There are people in Shanghai.
My friends, my family.
They have joined Operation Enduring Victory already.
It is for nothing.
We will all die.
We're going to be able to answer some of these questions.
I just want to know why I am here.
It doesn't make sense to me.
You were brought here because of your skill set.
No, that can't be right.
I am an art historian.
I know.
Dutch masters, Japanese calligraphy.
Gerhard Richter.
What does that matter Now
that is accurate.
Yes.
So these mechanical monstrosities, they don't just kill people.
They feed off.
Not just people.
All organic matter, Every living thing dissolved into nutrients.
Millennia of evolution.
Liquefied.
The miracle of life for Jesus,
buddy, buy a fuel.
In a word.
Yes, You did this.
Farah, That is he No, Doctor, Please tell him Tom Taik wants a word.
Don't, please.
You get Take fair.
I went here.
I want to discuss who?
So Mama, she was right.
Baden.
My mother.
She took her Bible Real.
Siri's not just Texas.
Global serious Pentecostal serious, favourite chapter revelations.
Now, I didn't always understand her on account of all that speaking in tongues and such.
But when she did use the word, it was always, in times this and the lake of fire that on kind of sinful lifestyles.
Speaking of which, mind if I smoke a tobacco cigarette?
Sorry, dialling my tastes run Classic compliments.
Your team tracked me down, but a price on my head 18 months now.
Still, the Malki was me.
I don't mind admitting and plenty of snakes, tigers chasing the bounty too.
But I kept the zig in to their zag
How'd you finger me?
I believe Dr Sobek listed you as an Alfa candidate.
Priority snatching grab.
Always suspected she had a little thing for me.
Hey, I don't suppose you got real coffee in this place?
You know, blood coffee, conflict cappuccinos.
Mr.
Tate, I'm clearing you to proceed.
Just go.
Previously worked for Farrow Automated Systems on the chariot lying self replication routines.
But I came here thinking this was a rendition.
When your people took me, I thought about time.
I've been tryingto swallow the guilt every day since
since, uh, would you like to take a moment?
No, no, no.
I just
I really hoped this Euro Dawn was a way to undo it.
All my work.
Yeah.
I'm sorry to say I was ever proud of it, but Ted could really sell a concept.
And in the labs, in the light of creation, that first test run.
When?
When you saw they understood their own structures, could we build themselves from memory and light?
There were no limits.
God, there were no limits.
C 02 data intact.
So you've heard the bad news and it's all true.
The Pharaoh plague is devouring the biosphere life itself will cease to exist.
What does that have to be?
The end.
What if we could give life a future?
What if we could build a kind of seed from which, on a dead planet life could blossom anew?
This's a hope of Project Zero Dawn
to create a super intelligent, fully automated terra forming system and bring life back from lifelessness.
What was such a system require?
At its core?
It would need a true eh I fully capable of making the trillions of decisions necessary to reconstitute the biosphere, An immortal guardian devoted to the re flourishing of life way.
Call it guy
Mother Nature as an aye aye.
But that's just the core of the system.
She will need to be surrounded and empowered by a comprehensive suite of subordinate functions.
Think of them as extensions of guy's mind, each dedicated to a specific purpose.
Now these aren't a eyes, but make no mistake.
Each presents an engineering challenge more profound than anything.
The human species is ever before attempted hardware that preserves, and then Jess states the billions of seeds and embryos from which life will be reborn.
The construction of underground facilities to hold it all.
And that's just the start way.
Don't have to build the entire system.
The beauty of a fully automated, terra forming system is that it can build itself Now.
Over the days to come, you'll learn how all these functions all these pieces that you'll be working on fit together.
How will race the clock to execute our harvest initiatives?
Right?
The software.
Build the tech in the facilities.
How will lock it down and seal it up before the inevitable occurs.
But even more important, you'll know how it doesn't end here.
How a guy will generate those deactivation codes General Harris talks about and build the transmission of raised broadcasting, shutting down the pharaoh robots for good.
How a guy will not just build but imagine any conceivable robot it needs to do its work across centuries
for detoxifying the earth ravaged atmosphere in poison sees
to the greening of the earth, from cryo preserved seed stocks to re wilding the earth with animal life.
And then, when all that is done, how a new generation of human beings spawned a cradle, facilities around the globe will partake of Apollo, the vast archive of human knowledge and cultural achievement from which they will learn of us our world
and most important
not to repeat our mistakes.
It's not an impossible dream.
It is within our grasp.
If we worked tirelessly and stop at nothing to achieve it,
we can't stop life from anything.
But if you will help me, help guy,
We can give it a future.
Join me and helped make that future really
whole earth destroyed, but then
remade.
Yes, by machine,
Machine of creation.
I was a bit did this
for life for us.
But why Harris then if it was part of Kaya, how'd it end up in the wreckage of a pharaoh robot?
And why does it want to kill me and Apollo?
The archive of knowledge?
What happened to that?
Into fists
taking over.
So
I'm just confused as you are.
Maybe the answers lie ahead.
You are now in possession of information regarding the true nature and purpose of project zeroed on.
Classified far above top secret.
As such, we regret that you cannot be allowed to leave this facility.
There are three options available to you at this point.
Please consider each carefully trained.
Counsellors are standing by to assist you in making your choice one participation.
You will be assigned to a sub project team based on your area of expertise.
You should be aware that the way forward will be difficult in the projects.
Outcome is uncertain.
You will be expected to work a minimum of eight hours per week and your communications with family members will be strictly limited and monitored in real time.
Upon successful completion of the project, you and your immediate family or two persons of your choosing will be transferred to really see um, seal habitat to live out the remainder of your natural lives to indefinite detention.
Should you choose to decline participation in Project zero Don, you will be confined indefinitely.
You will be given 48 hours to reconsider, after which your decision to refuse participation will be considered irrevocable.
Every reasonable effort will be made to make your term of confinement as comfortable as possible, but you will not be permitted contact with the outside world and death within 18 months due to the pharaoh, plague is inevitable When the zeroed on facilities abandoned.
Detainees who wish knobbed opt for medical euthanasia will be released.
Three medical euthanasia information you have just received understandably constant question.
The purpose of continuing to live if you would prefer to end your life.
At this point, pain free medical euthanasia is available.
A 48 hour waiting period is required, during which time you may instead up for participation or confinement.
Please notify a counsellor when you are ready to make your choice, or if you have further questions
for debriefing after presentation to It is vitally important that candidates choose to participate in a project zero Don, voluntarily and knowingly, without additional coercion and without value.
Judgement on the part of the counsellor confirmed for candidates that they were selected due to their skill sets and accomplishments, emphasised that they're dedicated.
Participation in Zero Don will increase the project's chances of success.
Frame participation in zero Don is an opportunity to respond actively in the face of an overwhelming threat.
Candidates may question the fairness of their selection, validates such objections as normal.
Even admirable responses emphasised the value of candidates expertise to the future, not just of humanity, but terrestrial life is a hole.
Likewise, candidates may block the morality of extending their life spans, and those have loved ones beyond zero day validate their hesitation, acknowledged that while the reward of Elysium is not fair, it will be earned, if possible, redirect their ethical misgivings towards greater commitment to the project.
When candidates challenge the plausibility of Project Zero, don permit them to review Dr Sobek's presentation as many times as they wish and allow access to supplemental articles.
Geo one through 20 allowed him to suspend the interview.
To fully process this documentation, a significant minority of candidates will elect for medical euthanasia.
It is important to receive this decision kindly and without judgement.
Advise them of the 48 hour waiting period during which counsellors will be available to discuss their decision.
Emphasised that euthanasia will not occur without repeated consent.
When the procedure is scheduled to take place, no one will be euthanised against her.
His well.
Candidates who elect indefinite detention must be informed that they have 48 hours to reverse their decision, after which the decision dating corrupt
of course, all to it
to be given the opportunity to rebuild what I, uh, damaged.
Well, I I don't feel worthy of it, but I do it absolutely.
I want to stress that this was never about your culpability.
Uh, it is to me, Doctor.
So back Margo, they were smart to get out of fair when they did, but but not one of us took it as a warning sign.
It just told ourselves we weren't cut out for the BTR, right?
Got balls.
But this the better than rapid innovation.
Better competing better than the next guy.
Better killing machine.
It's just amazing how centre and half of science fiction did nothing to swerve our species from the path of duty.
I'm done with that life.
I mean, I work hard twice as hard to learn this for my family to have a place in at least him.
I never thought I that there could be, uh, atonement,
you know.
Okay.
If you're still nauseous.
No, the inhibitors have kicked in.
I can't feel the back off my tongue.
I wish I could tell you and believe in this, but the damage is too great, too extensive to complete.
It is our respect to Dr Sobek's.
Forget Miriam.
No.
You know, life doesn't always find a way to keep going.
Sometimes it never comes back.
Like cities like the Congo.
Like chemo like us.
That's our reward.
A buried city full of terminal patients reading out the clock.
You grow old together with your loved ones.
In safety.
I don't have loved ones by suppose I could start a family.
I'm afraid not.
All inhabitants of Elysium will be medically sterilised.
The habitat capable of sustaining a starting base of 2000 individuals for up to 100 years is a huge challenge.
Dr.
Alpert, if the population grows instead of diminishes, everyone will be did inside 30 years.
I knew it.
I just couldn't bring myself to say the words.
I'm sorry.
Finish it.
The medical euthanasia.
I want no part off this.
I just want it over.
I see
protocols require a 48 hour waiting period after which,
you know,
you see to make sure I behave this time security for your protection.
Would you like to discuss how you're feeling?
I'll tell you.
Surprised?
No.
Flabbergasted.
Like my own man would say.
That vein pumping in his forehead.
I thought I thought you people were just completely under prepared for a space.
My project.
But now I can see its first.
Much worse.
So back is a total fantasist.
A dangerous fantasist.
This kind of blue Skying is
Jesus.
I'm sorry.
We're wasting each other's time.
I'm ready to leave now.
I'm afraid that's not possible.
Everything you're talking about here isn't possible.
I recommend you read the documents regarding your options.
I've seen enough.
I'm getting out of here.
What did you do?
You don't get your hands off me!
Alert!
Medical going inaccessible.
No,
no
Intruder!
Get her!
Whatever you do, don't die now!
Khalid!
God!
Yeah.
Hey,
I asked it out with him.
What?
The point of Artemus Walls.
I made it clear I wasn't on board for a global zoo.
We haven't exactly proved ourselves to be great custodians in the past 2000 years.
So the idea of a reconstituted biassed
Well, it's horrifying, isn't it?
A complete horror show?
We have no right to take a best guess at this stuff.
But the alternative
nothingness
for NATO penal this then
nothing with Charles Bronson running the show are respected.
He's got a passionate to him.
He's hot blooded.
So I said, I'll do it.
I'll put my all into this literally.
The project is done.
I'll take the medical options.
Thank you.
Counsellor said I might change my mind.
I told him that he didn't know me very well.
The life psych.
I'll do the dirty work, but I want no part of this Hasidic continue ated future on offer on an outdoors man never did like the feel of solid state lighting on Muskie
and a wee bit of a claustrophobic anyway.
Zero don't.
It is odd in a way,
an expression on the grandest scale.
There is so much unfairness.
Why was I chosen?
Was it decided by committee?
I'll go with him.
My family will be saved because I happen to graduate in art history.
Is this right,
Doctor?
Super Christina Soup.
Yes.
I met a man, another historian, his fields off our house and the new materialists.
But he once attended one of my tools.
Another on a fair chance off over many people in the auditorium that we should both be here now.
And yet I feel more accepting off my fate.
No, it is not fair.
Not at all, but for the sake of my family.
For the sake auf art art is alive.
It must be able to speak from beyond history and echo in the future, not perish into oblivion.
This opportunity I must do this
now.
Those lame FBI black Hanson mocking Bird back in the day,
I enjoyed school in them, but maybe I went into hard on this poor counsellor.
She was cute and just going down the checklist.
After all, you couldn't expect her to see how ridiculous here of these ambitions are.
God's own budget surrounded a kid playing with a hologram sculptor palms up winning.
I'm just calling it like it is.
Look, Mama, making nature now.
If nature is so important, why not let nature take its course
extension?
That's natural Is Euro don and no man that ain't pic.
It's the one that she will be called on a abomination back home and you know it.
That's why you're hiding it.
Meanwhile, my little honey of a counsellor, she's munching the inside of her cheek.
Bad habit.
She killed one of her nails to you.
Just one.
Not your date was a little sleepy, so her quota slipping away said I assume you intend to decline the assignment.
Mr.
Tate.
You kidding me?
18 months hard labour, in exchange for 30 years lounging around Coliseum watching porn.
Sign me up.
Power's down.
Is there another road?
I've done this before.
Just need my focus.
Look,
here we go.
Another one of these.
I need to find the right configuration.
Done.
I should cheque the door nearby.
Yeah,
that
no
found one looks intact.
That should do the trick.
Let's get that door open.
Hey, I'm done with threats and confidence.
Okay?
Somehow he managed to instal in h emitter noted backwards, Everything's in reverse.
I don't get paid to clean up or it's Mrs if you want it fixed.
Sent him up to storage for a new admit or not me.
Park around
that did it.
Door should have power now to see what lies beyond it.
Collapse.
They're here.
Avoid contact.